<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An Account of the late barbarous proceedings of the Earl of Tyrconnel and his soldiers against the poor Protestants in Ireland with their killing and driving some thousands out of Cork and Lymmerick stark naked in the cold, their besieging Bandon, taking the Honourable Capt. Boyle, and their bloody association to destroy all the Protestants of that kingdom.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1689</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A25337</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A306B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R1178</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12953637</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12953637</idno>
            <idno type="VID">96016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A25337)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 96016)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2:55)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An Account of the late barbarous proceedings of the Earl of Tyrconnel and his soldiers against the poor Protestants in Ireland with their killing and driving some thousands out of Cork and Lymmerick stark naked in the cold, their besieging Bandon, taking the Honourable Capt. Boyle, and their bloody association to destroy all the Protestants of that kingdom.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for W. Downing ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1689.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Tyrconnel, Richard Talbot, --  Earl of, 1630-1691.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  History --  War of 1689-1691.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:96016:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 15 -->
            <head>AN ACCOUNT Of the late Barbarous Proceedings of the Earl of Tyrconnel<lb/>
And his Soldiers, againſt the poor PROTESTANTS in <hi>Ireland:</hi> With their Killing and Driving ſome Thouſands out of <hi>Cork</hi> and <hi>Lymmerick</hi> Stark Naked in the Cold: Their Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſieging <hi>Bandon,</hi> Taking the Honourable Capt. <hi>Boyle,</hi> and their Bloody Aſſociation to deſtroy all the <hi>Proteſtants</hi> of that <hi>Kingdom.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THE Lord <hi>Tyrconnel,</hi> the late King <hi>James</hi>'s Deputy of the Kingdom of <hi>Ireland,</hi> ſince the ſaid Kings Departure, and Abdication of the Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> being as it ſeems reſolved to keep the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom is a reſerve and refuge for his Maſter upon occaſion, or by a Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gorous ſeeming Preparation for War, to lay a ſeaſonable and ſure foundation for Tollerable and Advantagious Conditions for himſelf, behav'd <unclear>himſelf with ſome</unclear> ſort of pretended Conſcience and Mercy towards the p<gap reason="illegible: under-inked" extent="3+ letters">
                  <desc>•••…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible: under-inked" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> down that Kingdom, until the News of the Prince of O<gap reason="illegible: under-inked" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ge  <gap reason="illegible: under-inked" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> King, which ſo enraged him, that he publickly Swore, that he would <gap reason="illegible: under-inked" extent="5+ letters">
                  <desc>•••••…</desc>
               </gap>g<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed on all the <hi>Proteſtants</hi> in that Kingdom. And about the ſame time receiving both Arms and Ammunition from <hi>France,</hi> as alſo full aſſurance of the late King with a good ſupply of Men and Arms, would arrive there to his and the papiſts Aſſiſtance in that Kingdom, and then immediately threw of the Diſguiſe of Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice, pretended in his late Proclamation, and, give publick Liberty and encou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ragement to hls Souldiers and Officers, to plunder and deſtroy the Proteſtants, as they ſhould think fit. Whereupon the Papiſts ins moſt of the great Towns in <hi>Munſter</hi> aſſemble, and firſt ſtriping Men, Women, and Children, they Drive them out of the Towns, and leave them to the Mercy of the reſt about the Roads. In <hi>Cork,</hi> they gathered Three Thouſand proteſtants, Men, Women, and Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren, and Robbing them of all their Effects in their Habitations, they without regard to Modeſty, Charity, or Sex, ſtrip them ſtark naked, and drive them out of the Town; the Soldiers Slapping and Beating them with Cudgels, and uſing moſt Barbarous and Undecent Actions to the Women. In <hi>Lymrick</hi> they have done the ſame, driving out, and abuſing ſome Hundreds in the Cold, without one Rag about them.</p>
            <p>The Honouroble Captain <hi>Boyle,</hi> by Treachery of ſome abot him, they have Teken, and are in cloſe purſuit after the Earl of <hi>Inchiqueen</hi> the greateſt prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant Champion in <hi>Munſter:</hi> The ſtrong Town of <hi>Bandon</hi> they have ſent Eight Thouſand Men to Beſiege: and threaten moſt horribly to deſtroy, Man, Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man and Child, unleſs they yield upon Summons; and it is remarkable, that one <hi>Cartie,</hi> an Officer in <hi>Bandon,</hi> deſiting leave to go out of the Town, the proteſtants having Diſarm'd his Company before, for fear of their Villany, they freely gave him leave, and the Villain had ſcarce got half a mile from the Town, when he meets with Two proteſtant <hi>Engliſh</hi> Children, a Boy and a Girl, and alighting, he Barbarouſly Murthered, cutting their Throats, and ripping them up. Theſe are the firſt ſo Bloody Attempts, which ſo nearly reſemble their Beginnings in their laſt ſo horrid Rebellion in Forty One, that unleſs ſpeedy Succor be ſent, (whibh God Almighty grant) we may quickly hear of the utter and Barbarous Extirpation of all the proteſtants, beſides the hazard of not being able to recover that Kingdom, without the Expence and Trouble of a long and tedious war.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>W. Downing</hi> in <hi>Bartholomew-Cloſe.</hi> 1689.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
